Bruno Baère Pedrazzi Lomba de Araujo

mail: bruno.baere@gmail.com phone: +5521996826336

SUMMARY

I am motivated by challenging tasks and to teach others about what I have learned. My experience as both an academic researcher and as a systems analyst helps me to approach, to model, to understand problems, and to develop a solution. My analytical skills have been proven useful in detecting and preventing bugs and problems in systems modeling.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Analyst

Feb 2020 - Present

Instituto Tecgraf – PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group C++ developer in v3o2 project.

Product Owner Feb 2018 - Jan 2020

Instituto Tecgraf – PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group

Product Owner in v3o2 project. Responsible for the product value of various parts of the software dealing with geology and geophysics. Responsibilities included: understand the client needs, propose a solution, create user stories for the development team, and manage client expectations. I also wrote and maintained the product manual for the parts I was responsible for, and helped restructure the recruitment interview process.

Senior Systems Analyst / Researcher

Aug 2011 - Feb 2018

Instituto Tecgraf - PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics Group

C++ developer in v3o2 project, a seismic and well data visualizer for Petrobras running on RedHat/CentOS 5 using OpenGL, GTK+, boost, and Qt. For QA used GoogleTest framework, valgrind, and cppcheck. I organized and wrote the documentation of the development environment setup for home office, and worked on the upgrade to RedHat/CentOS 6. I also presented with colleagues a 2 day workshop on Scrum for team members.

Researcher

Apr 2009 - Aug 2011

ICAD/Visionlab - PUC-Rio

Researcher in games, digital entertainment and simulations. C# programmer in a joint project with CENPES and USP. Developed a shade tree editor in C# and Windows GDI for building DirectX shaders for the proof tank visualizer project.

Undergraduate teaching assistant

Mar 2009 - Dec 2009

Department of Computer Science – PUC-Rio

Worked as UTA for Introduction to Programming (C language) and Data Structures. Gave extra classes at Saturdays and post-class hours, resolving exercises and exams.

Intern Oct 2008 - Mar 2009

ICA - Laboratório de Inteligência Computacional Aplicada – PUC-Rio

C# developer. Worked at FxANEEL project, developing part of the user interface with WindowsForms and XML. Developed a wrapper for GSLIB library in C# and created the model for library documentation used by the lab.

Scientific Initiation

Aug 2006 - Aug 2008

ICAD/Visionlab – PUC-Rio

Development of a simulation library for Torque Game Engine. Researched game en-

gine use in fluid simulations, programmed in C++ using OGRE rendering engine. Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship.

PUBLICATIONS

Maria das G. de A. Chagas, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Waldecir V. Faria, Cezar G. Loureiro, Maria I. M. M. Carmo, Nelson J. Donato, Tathiana S. T. Silva, Victoria D. Maidantchik, Yann L. M. de M. Marques. *Design de Jogos de RPG Digitais: Uma investigação sobre a experiência de jogo*. In: Proceedings of XIV Brazilian Symposium on Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2015), Teresina, Piauí, Brazil, November 2015.

Paula C. Ribeiro, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Alberto Raposo. *ComFiM: A Cooperative Serious Game to Encourage the Development of Communicative Skills between Children with Autism*. In: Proceedings of the XIII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2014), Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 2014. DOI: 10.1109/SBGAMES.2014.19

Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo, Bruno Feijó. *Evaluating dynamic difficulty adaptivity in shoot'em up games*. In: Proceedings of the XII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2013), São Paulo, Brazil, October 2013.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Computer Graphics

2010 - 2012

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro – PUC-Rio

Advisor: Bruno Feijó

Dissertation title: A study on dynamic difficulty adaptivity for games

Granted 2 years of CAPES scholarship

GPA/CR: 3.54 (4.0 scale) / 89%

2005 - 2009

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering
Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro – PUC-Rio

Minor: Advanced studies in Mathematics

Final project title: A shade tree editor for OGRE materials

Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship

Language proficiency: Cambridge English FCE grade B2

2003

EXTRA-CURRICULAR COURSES

Digital Product Management: Modern Fundamentals 2020 University of Virginia on Coursera, 16h.

Fundamentals of Project Planning and Management 2018
University of Virginia on Coursera, 8h.

O setor de games no Brasil: panorama, carreiras e oportunidades 2018 Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul. 30h.

Introduction to User Experience Design 2017 Georgia Institute of Technology on Coursera, 10h. Certificate V8K283SJ8Q9T.

Gamification 2016

University of Pennsylvania on Coursera, 48h. Certificate WEVTGH9S3WK5.

A complexidade sensível: Um paralelo entre videogames e arte 2016 Universidade Estadual de Campinas on Coursera, 14h. Certificate EC8XZEZZ26HY.

Oil & Gas Industry Operations and Markets

2016

Duke University on Coursera, 10h. Certificate WEVTGH9S3WK5.

Geologia do petróleo para não-geólogos

2014

ABGP - Associação Brasileira de Geólogos do Petróleo, 20h.

CERTIFICATIONS Certified Scrum Product Owner

Valid: Mar 2014 - Mar 2022

Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959

Certified Scrum Master Valid: Jan 2014 - Mar 2022

Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES Co-organizer of PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam Helped organize PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam.

Jan 2018, Jan 2020

Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing 2016 - Present Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing, an Elsevier journal. ISSN 1875-9521.

Researcher at PUC-Rio's Game Design Research Group

2013 - Present Associate researcher in the Arts & Design Department research group under prof. Maria das Graças Chagas advisory. Themes include player-NPC relationship and artificial intelligence.

SBGames 2011's Independent Games Festival contestant 2011 Contestant with the game Lights Out. Awarded with the third place in people's choice in the Art Game cathegory.

GAMES

Lights Out

2011

A puzzle-like art game for 2 players made in GameMaker 8.1. Presented at SBGames 2011, FILE Games 2012, Festival Games Brasil 2013. Role: programmer (GameMaker Scripting Language) and 2D artist.

Seu Espião Safado!

2011

A print-and-play dice game for 3 players where 2 agents are trying to uncover a spy's secret (Brazilian Portuguese only). Role: game designer.

You Are Trash! 2009

A Java 2D game mix of puzzle and platformer, made in the Gamerama project. Role: programmer and game designer.

OTHER INFORMATION

Personal homepage: http://killerasus.github.io

GitHub: https://github.com/killerasus

Lattes curriculum: http://lattes.cnpq.br/0738342776987656